# Syed Azfar Ali, (ACCA)

## **ACADEMIC QUALIFICATIONS**

Member Association of Certified Chartered Accountants— (ACCA)

2013 – 2018

**BSc.** (Honors) in Accounting and Finance — (Oxford Brookes University)

2018 - 2018

#### **PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCES**

#### **Excelsious Ltd.**

An accounting and technology outsourcing company headquartered in London, United Kingdom.

## Business Analyst July 2018 - Present

My main activities as a business analyst are as follows:

- > Analysis and implementation of business processes and solutions.
- ➤ Liaison with technical staff to ensure appropriate end result is provided as per the requirements.
- > Performing functional testing once a module is developed and deployed.
- > Analysis on how to improve the business processes and procedures.

#### Functional Consultant April 2017 – June 2018

My main activities as a business analyst are as follows:

- > Analysis and implementation of business processes and solutions.
- ➤ Liaison with technical staff to ensure appropriate end result is provided as per the requirements.
- > Performing functional testing once a module is developed and deployed.
- ➤ Analysis on how to improve the business processes and procedures

## Accountant May 2016 – March 2017

My main activities as an accounting supervisor were as follows:

- > Data migration and setup of accounting software.
- Supervising accounting, taxation and bookkeeping assignments.
- > Statutory submissions to Companies House and HMRC

## S.M Suhail & Co Chartered Accountants — External Audit Trainee

August 2015 – November 2015

Some of the notable clients that I have worked on includes;

International Textiles Limited, Arwen Tech (Pvt.) Ltd and some other Not for Profits organizations.

#### **Tanzeem & Co Chartered Accountants** — External Audit Trainee

October 2014 – July 2015

My main activities as an audit trainee were as follows: conducting audit procedures to ensure that financial statements of client show a true and fair view, through research, analysis and cumulative audit knowledge.

### **Arif Habib Commodities** — Research and Business Development Executive

August 2014 – September 2014

My main activities at Arif Habib were as follows: to find potential clients and perform analysis of the movements in the prices of commodities in the mercantile exchange market.



## **Aspiring Data Analyst**

#### **SUMMARY**

I have 4 years of working experience in accounting and technology firms. I have established expertise related to automation of day to day accounting task. I plan to excel in the field of data analysis and to become a Professional Data Scientist and bring more automation and data-driven decision making into the field.

#### **PERSONAL DETAILS**

Father Name: Syed Laiq Ali Date of Birth: 09/May/1994 Nationality: Pakistani

Religion: Islam

#### **CONTACT DETAILS**

Email: azfarbkhr@gmail.com Mobile: 0092-332-8355627 Skype: azfar@accountant.com Address: Gulshan-e-Iqbal, Block 6,

Karachi, Pakistan.

## **RELEVANT TOOLS**

- ➤ MS Office, G-Suite
- ➤ XERO, QuickBooks Online, Sage One, Sage50, Capium, WaveApps (Accounting Software)
- ➤ Receipt-Bank (Automated Data Entry)
- ➤ Power BI (Data Visualization Tool)
- ➤ T-SQL (Database Language)
- ➤ Bitrix24, InfusionSoft (CRM)

#### **CERTIFICATIONS**

- ➤ HEC Equivalency to M.Com for ACCA Membership
- > XERO Certified Adviser
- ➤ XERO Payroll Adviser (UK)
- QuickBooks Online Partner
- ➤ Microsoft: T-SQL Query Data